let's look at the solution to our
predictor impact quiz where we consider
the intel pentium 4 price code processor
that spends 30 cycles until it finally
resolves branches uses branch prediction
and multiple instructions per cycle so
that in a program where 20 of
instructions are branches
and where one percent of branches are
mispredicted it gets a cpi of 0.5
overall in this cpi
we are getting
some ideal cpi plus for branches that we
mispredict 1 of the time
we pay a
30 cycle penalty because we resolve
branches really in the 31st cycle
and that means that the ideal cpi
is equal to the actual cpi we are
getting minus
the cpi penalty from branches
and if we multiply this out we get 0.06
so x here the ideal cpi with a perfect
branch vector
would be
0.44
now when two percent of branches are
mispredicted our cpi will be equal to
x plus
for branches
we mispredict
two percent of the time and we pay a 30
cycle penalty so we get 0.44 plus
this which multiplies out to 0.12
for an overall cpi now of 0.56
so the key to solving this again was
that we were given the actual cpi we
needed to compute what the ideal cpi is
after we remove the branch penalty
and then we compute the new branch
penalty and add it to this ideal cpi to
get this answer